Castle-Bache Collection 1683-1922 Mss.Film.1506
American Philosophical Society
- Series I. Correspondence, 1683-1922; 3 lin. feet
  - To Thomas Hewson Bache, 1879 Nov. 23; Heard, J. Theo (Reel 5)
  - To Thomas Hewson Bache, 1879 Nov. 29; McAllister, John A. (Reel 5)
  - To Thomas Hewson Bache, 1879 Nov. 30; McAllister, John A. (Reel 5)
  - Invitation to the wedding of Irene Filtsch Dabadie and Walter Scott Andrews, 1879; Orig. and copy (Reel 5)
  - To Thomas Hewson Bache, 1880 Apr. 26; McAllister, John A. (Reel 5)
  - To Alfred Elwyn, 1880 May 31; Bache, Charles Meigs, 1829-1890 (Reel 5)
  - To Thomas Hewson Bache, 1880 Dec. 12; McAllister, John A. (Reel 5)
  - To Thomas Hewson Bache, 1880 Dec. 21; McAllister, John A. (Reel 5)
  - To Thomas Hewson Bache, 1881 Jan. 7; McAllister, John A. (Reel 5)
  - To Thomas Hewson Bache, 1881 Apr. 5; McAllister, John A. (Reel 5)
  - To Thomas Hewson Bache, 1881 June 29; McAllister, John A. (Reel 5)
  - To Albert Dabadie Bache, 1884 Oct. 31; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 5)
  - To Albert Dabadie Bache, 1884 Nov. 3; Bache, Louis (Reel 5)
  - To Albert Dabadie Bache, 1885 Jan. 29; Bache, Louis (Reel 5)
  - To Thomas Hewson Bache, 1885 June 9; Homes, Henry A. (Reel 5)
  - To Thomas Hewson Bache, 1886 July 19; Homes, Henry A. (Reel 5)
  - To Thomas Hewson Bache, 1887 July 14; Bache, Charles Meigs, 1829-1890 (Reel 5)
  - To Thomas Hewson Bache, 1887 Nov. 14; Bache, Charles Meigs, 1829-1890 (Reel 5)
  - Financial statement, 1888 Jan. 9; Bache, Thomas Hewson (Reel 5)
  - To Thomas Hewson Bache, 1888 Jan. 12; Bache, Charles Meigs, 1829-1890 (Reel 5)
  - To Thomas Hewson Bache, 1888 Feb. 14; Bache, Charles Meigs, 1829-1890 (Reel 5)
  - To Thomas Hewson Bache, 1888 Oct. 13; Bache, Charles Meigs, 1829-1890 (Reel 5)
  - Lines address to W. Green from Boston, 1888 (Reel 5)
  - To Thomas Hewson Bache, 1889 Feb. 11; Bache, Charles Meigs, 1829-1890 (Reel 5)
  - To Thomas Hewson Bache, 1889 June 4; Bache, Albert Dabadie, 1832-1895 (Reel 5)
  - To Thomas Hewson Bache, 1889 Oct. 31; Andrews, S. (Reel 5)
  - To S. Andrews, 1889 Nov. 1; Bache, Thomas Hewson (Reel 5)
  - To Thomas Hewson Bache, 1889 Dec. 1; Bache, Charles Meigs, 1829-1890 (Reel 5)
  - To Thomas Hewson Bache, 1889 Dec. 31; Bache, Franklin (Reel 5)
  - To Thomas Hewson Bache, 1890 Jan. 17; Gutzwiller (Reel 5)
  - To Albert Dabadie Bache, 1890 Mar. 29; Ransonnet, Gita (Reel 5)
  - To Mrs. Fetterman, 1890 July 13; Bache, Henrietta Maria (Reel 5)
  - To Albert Dabadie Bache, 1890 Nov. 28; Beebe, Orlando (Reel 5)
  - To Thomas Hewson Bache, 1891 Jan. 8; Bache, Henrietta Maria (Reel 5)
  - To Thomas Hewson Bache, 1891 Feb. 18; Bache, Henrietta Maria (Reel 5)
  - To Thomas Hewson Bache, 1891 Feb. 25; Bache, Albert Dabadie, 1832-1895 (Reel 5)
  - To Thomas Hewson Bache, 1891 Mar. 31; Bache, Henrietta Maria (Reel 5)
  - To Thomas Hewson Bache, 1891 July 9; Bache, Albert Dabadie, 1832-1895 (Reel 5)
  - To Thomas Hewson Bache, 1891 Aug. 6; Bache, Albert Dabadie, 1832-1895 (Reel 5)
  - To Thomas Hewson Bache, 1891 Aug. 24; Barry, J. N. D. (Reel 5)
  - To Thomas Hewson Bache, 1892 Apr. 8; Bache, Albert Dabadie, 1832-1895 (Reel 5)
  - To Thomas Hewson Bache, 1892 Apr. 21; Bache, Albert Dabadie, 1832-1895 (Reel 5)
  - To Thomas Hewson Bache, 1892 May 2; Bache, Franklin (Reel 5)
  - To Thomas Hewson Bache, 1892 June 7; Bache, Franklin (Reel 5)
  - To Thomas Hewson Bache, 1892 July 17; Bache, Franklin (Reel 5)
  - To Thomas Hewson Bache, 1892 Oct. 15; Bache, Albert Dabadie, 1832-1895 (Reel 5)
  - To Thomas Hewson Bache, 1892 Oct. 17; Bache, Albert Dabadie, 1832-1895 (Reel 5)
  - To Thomas Hewson Bache, 1892 Oct. 24; Bache, Franklin (Reel 5)
  - Memorandum of account, 1892; Wiling, Mrs. Bingham (Reel 5)
  - To Thomas Hewson Bache, 1893 Jan. 17; Bache, Margaret Hartman (Reel 5)
  - To Thomas Hewson Bache, 1893 Apr. 3; Bache, Albert Dabadie, 1832-1895 (Reel 5)
  - To Thomas Hewson Bache, 1893 Apr. 14; Bache, Margaret Hartman (Reel 5)
  - To Thomas Hewson Bache, 1893 July 28; Bache, Margaret Hartman (Reel 5)
  - To Thomas Hewson Bache, 1893 Aug. 29; Bache, Franklin (Reel 5)
  - To George Maurice Abbot, 1894 Aug. 27; Sharp, William S. (Reel 5)
  - To Thomas Hewson Bache, 1895 Sept. 30; Keith, Charles (Reel 5)
  - To Thomas Hewson Bache, 1896 Jan. 12; Pepper, William Platt (Reel 5)
  - To Thomas Hewson Bache, 1896 Nov. 16; Wister, Sarah B. (Reel 5)
  - Receipt from silversmith, 1897 Dec. 7; Kreider, S. (Reel 5)
  - Notes concerning Bache family Christmas dinner, 1898 Dec. (Reel 5)
  - Receipt for items from estate of Thomas Hewson Bache, 1913 Jan. 4; Bache, Franklin (Reel 5)
  - To Franklin Bache, 1915 June 16; Library of Congress (Reel 5)
  - To Franklin Bache, 1916 Mar. 16; Thompson, Samuel H. (Reel 5)
  - Materials relating to military service, 1861-1865, 1916-1919; Bache, Charles Meigs, 1829-1890 (Reel 5)
  - To George W. Doughty, 1917 Jan. 11; Cy; Bache, Franklin (Reel 5)
  - To Franklin Bache, 1917 Jan. 17; Doughty, George W. (Reel 5)
  - To Franklin Bache, 1917 Jan. 18; Doughty, George W. (Reel 5)
  - To Franklin Bache, 1917 Feb. 7; Doughty, George W. (Reel 5)
  - To Franklin Institute. Librarian, 1919 Apr. 26; Cy; Whitney, J. S. (Reel 5)
  - To United States. Secretary of the Treasury, 1921 Mar. 22; Bache, Franklin (Reel 5)
  - To Franklin Bache, 1921 Mar. 24; United States. Treasury Department (Reel 5)
  - To Harjes, 1922 Apr. 25; Cy; Bache, Franklin (Reel 5)
  - To Franklin Bache, 1922 Apr. 27; Alexander Dallas Bache Public School (Reel 5)
  - To Alexander Dallas Bache Public School, 1922 May 1; Cy; Bache, Franklin (Reel 5)
  - To Franklin Bache, 1922 May 2; Alexander Dallas Bache Public School (Reel 5)
  - To Franklin Bache, 1922 May 30; Harjes (Reel 5)
  - To Franklin Bache, 1922 June 13; Harjes (Reel 5)
  - To Margaret Hartman Markoe, n.d. (Monday); Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 5)
  - To Margaret Hartman Markoe, n.d. (Thurs.); Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 5)
  - To Margaret Hartman Markoe, n.d. (Thurs.); Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 5)
  - To Margaret Hartman Markoe, n.d. (Sat.; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 5)
  - To Benjamin Franklin, n.d.; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 5)
  - To Benjamin Franklin, n.d.; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 5)
  - To Benjamin Franklin, n.d.; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 5)
  - To Benjamin Franklin, n.d.; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 5)
  - To Benjamin Franklin, n.d.; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 5)
  - To Margaret Hartman Markoe, n.d.; ADfs; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 5)
  - To Margaret Hartman Markoe, n.d.; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 5)
  - To Margaret Hartman Markoe, n.d.; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 5)
  - To Margaret Hartman Markoe, n.d.; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 5)
  - To Margaret Hartman Markoe, n.d.; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 5)
  - To Margaret Hartman Markoe, n.d.; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 5)
  - To Margaret Hartman Markoe, n.d.; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 5)
  - To Margaret Hartman Markoe, n.d.; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 5)
  - Abrege, Analise, et Remarques... sur divers parties des Belles Lettres de l'Abbé Rolin, n.d.; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 5)
  - Essay on writing, n.d.; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 5)
  - Extraits des Arts et Metiers concernant l'Art de Faire le Papier, n.d.; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 5)
  - Fifth Book of Euclid, n.d.; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 5)
  - Miscellaneous Hints on Colds, n.d.; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 5)
  - Notes on history, n.d.; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 5)
  - Notes on John Adams' Defence of the Constitution, n.d.; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 5)
  - To Aglae Dabadie, n.d.; Bache, Franklin (Reel 5)
  - To Benjamin Franklin Bache, n.d.; Bache, Sarah (Reel 5)
    Published in The Collector, March 1926
  - To William Bache, n.d.; Orig. and typescript; Bache, Sarah (Reel 5)
  - Record of Civil War military service, n.d.; Bache, Thomas Hewson (Reel 5)
  - To Peter Markoe, n.d.; Bereshoud, John (Reel 5)
  - To Peter Markoe, n.d.; Duane, Margaret Hartman (Reel 5)
  - To Peter Markoe, n.d.; Cy; Duane, Margaret Hartman (Reel 5)
  - Blank passport form to be issued by Benjamin Franklin, n.d. (Reel 5)
    From original at the William L. Clements Library
  - Logic, 1st part, n.d.; Franklin, William Temple (Reel 5)
  - Notebook on Natural Philosophy, with sketches, n.d.; Franklin, William Temple (Reel 5)
  - Science notes, n.d.; Franklin, William Temple (Reel 5)
  - "Honoriad", n.d. (Reel 5)
  - List of European correspondents and members of the American Philosophical Society (Reel 5)
  - List of expenses, n.d. (Reel 5)
  - To William Temple Franklin, n.d.; Barbé de Marbois, François (Reel 5)
  - Remarques sur l'education, n.d.; Le Veillard, Elisabeth Bellamy (Reel 5)
  - To Benjamin Franklin, n.d.; Cy and typescript; Vergennes, Charles Gravier, comte de (Reel 5)
- Series II. Genealogical material, 1823-1945
  Genealogical material is arranged in alphabetical order by family name.
  - Bache. Notes on the English genealogy of the Bache family, n.d. (Reel 6)
  - Bache. Genealogy of the Bache family. Notes and correspondence, 1925-1927 (Reel 6)
  - Bache. Genealogy of the Bache family. Notes and correspondence, 1926-1933 (Reel 6)
  - Bache. Materials relating to the genealogy of the Bache family, 1932-1933 (Reel 6)
  - Bache. Genealogy of the Bache family. Notes and correspondence, 1933-1937 (Reel 6)
  - Bache. Miscellaneous items relating to Bache family genealogy, 1926-1941 (Reel 6)
  - Bache. The Franklin Ancestry and Descendants in the Colonel Louis Bache Line (2 copies) (Reel 6)
  - Bache. Various items relating to Bache, Johnston, and Castle family history (Reel 6)
  - Bache. Catalogue of items up for auction from the estates of Nannie T. Bache and Franklin Bache, etc., 1946 (Reel 6)
  - Bache. Materials relating to the Bache residence in Mannheim, Pa., n.d. (Reel 6)
  - Dabadie. Genealogy of the Dabadie family, miscellaneous notes, 1937 (Reel 6)
  - Duane. Genealogy of the Duane family, miscellaneous notes, n.d. (Reel 6)
  - Ellicott. Genealogy of the Ellicott family, notes and correspondence, 1908-1937 (Reel 6)
  - Ellicott. Miscellaneous items relating to the Bache-Ellicott genealogy, 1937-1945 (Reel 6)
  - Folger. Genealogy of the Folger family, miscellaneous notes, n.d. (Reel 6)
  - Franklin. Copies of documents relating to the marriage of Benjamin Franklin (typescript), 1895 (Reel 6)
  - Franklin. Genealogy of the Franklin family, miscellaneous notes, n.d. (Reel 6)
  - Franklin. Materials relating to the genealogies of the Franklin and Bache families (Reel 6)
  - Franklin. Miscellaneous newspaper obituaries of Benjamin Franklin's descendants (Reel 6)
  - Franklin. Materials relating to portraits and possessions of the Franklin family, 1823-1829 (Reel 6)
  - Franklin. Papers pertaining to various Franklin family portraits, n.d. (Reel 7)
  - Franklin. Miscellaneous notes on the history of the Franklin family and portraits of Benjamin Franklin (Reel 7)
  - Franklin. Notes and correspondence relating to Franklin family portraits, 1856-1938 (Reel 7)
  - Franklin. Charles Coleman Sellers, photocopy of catalogue of Benjamin Franklin portraits published in Benjamin Franklin in Portraiture, 1962 (Reel 7)
  - Franklin. Catalogue listing items for sale from estate of Ellen Duane Davis, including Franklin family papers, 1924 (Reel 7)
  - Franklin. Newspaper clipping regarding Samuel A. Green's gift of Benjamin Franklin books to Boston Public Library, 1879 (Reel 7)
  - Franklin. Catalogue of books up for auction which came from the libraries of Benjamin Franklin, William Franklin, William Temple Franklin, 1947 (Reel 7)
  - Franklin. Materials relating to the portrait of Benjamin Franklin by David Martin, 1875-1876 (Reel 7)
  - Franklin. Unsigned notes about portrait of Benjamin Franklin, 1876 May 8 (Reel 7)
  - Franklin. Unsigned notes about portrait of Benjamin Franklin, 1877 Feb. 9 (Reel 7)
  - Franklin. Materials relating to Benjamin Franklin's house, 1935-1936 (Reel 7)
  - Hardtman. Notes on Hardtman family genealogy, n.d. (Reel 7)
  - Markoe. Genealogy of Markoe family, notes and correspondence, 1934-1937 (Reel 7)
  - Markoe. Account of the Prom branch of the Markoe family, 1854 July 14 (Reel 7)
  - Ray. Materials relating to the genealogy of the Ray family, 1932 Sept. (Reel 7)
  - Read. Genealogy of the Read family, notes and correspondence, 1940 Sept. 21 (Reel 7)
  - Trigg. Genealogy of Nannie Trigg Bache (typescript), 1937 Sept. 1 (Reel 7)
  - Trigg. Genealogy of the Trigg family, notes and correspondence, 1932-1933 (Reel 7)
  - Trigg. Genealogy of the Trigg family (typescript), n.d. (Reel 7)
- Series III. Printed material, 1753-1941; 51 items
  - "Alexander Dallas Bache and his connection with the Franklin Institute of the State of Pennsylvania," Proceedings of the APS 84 (1941): 145-149, Allen, Henry Butler (Reel 7)
  - Enrichidion... Manuale Latino-Graecum (Geneva: Lousi Caille, 1769), (1715), Anonymous (Reel 7)
  - "Daily Advertiser Established... to the Supreme Executive Council of Pennsylvania," July 1780, Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 7)
  - "The world's oldest city", Bache, Charles Meigs, 1829-1890 (Reel 7)
  - "Published music of Francis Edward Bache", Bache, Francis Edward (Reel 7)
  - "Some incidents in the life of Benjamin Franklin," Proceedings of the Numismatic and Antiquarian Society of Philadelphia (June 1928), Bache, Franklin (Reel 7)
  - "Where is Franklin's first chart of the Gulf Stream?" Proceedings of the APS 76 (1936):731-731, Bache, Franklin (Reel 7)
  - Miscellaneous printed essays, Bache, Kentish (Reel 7)
  - An Inaugural Experimental Dissertation... (Philadelphia: T. Dobson, 1794), Bache, William (Reel 7)
  - An Ode to Bogle (Philadelphia: printed for J. Dreer, 1865), Biddle, Nicholas (Reel 7)
  - A Semi-Annual Oration on the Origins of Pestilential Diseases (Philadelphia: Thomas and Samuel F. Bradford, 1799), Caldwell, Charles (Reel 7)
  - A Series of Letters Addressed to Thomas Jefferson... by Tacitus (Philadelphia: Thomas Smith, 1802), Evans, Thomas (Reel 7)
  - Eloge Civique de Benjamin Franklin (Paris: J. R. Lottin, G. L. Bailly, 1790), Fauchet, Abbé (Reel 7)
  - Statement of Appellant, Supreme Court of the United States (1840), Frevall, Peter E. (Reel 7)
  - Eulogy on Prof. Alexander Dallas Bache (Washington: GPO, 1872), Henry, Joseph (Reel 7)
  - Diario de un Crucero (Mahon: 1835), Israel, John and Henry Lundt (Reel 8)
  - Engraved advertisement, Malcolm, James Peller (Reel 8)
  - Mezzotint of Benjamin Franklin (1787) with documents and correspondence, Peale, Charles Willson (Reel 8)
  - An Epistle to the National Meeting of Friends in Dublin (Philadelphia: Franklin and Hall, 1757), Pike, Joseph (Reel 8)
  - A Sketch of Mrs. Elizabeth Russell (Nashville: M.E. Church, 1888), Preston, Thomas L. (Reel 8)
  - Franklin Bache, Chemist (Philadelphia, 1922), Smith, Edgar Fahs, 1854-1928 (Reel 8)
  - Eulogium on Benjamin Franklin (Philadelphia: Benjamin Franklin Bache, 1792), Smith, William (Reel 8)
  - Eulogium on Benjamin Franklin (Philadelphia: Benjamin Franklin Bache, 1792), Smith, William (Reel 8)
  - "My Dear Dr. Franklin," Woman's Home Companion (July 1927), Stifler, James Madison (Reel 8)
  - Epicteti Enrichidion (Paris: Phillipe Denis Pierres, 1782), Villebrune, J. Lefebvre de (Reel 8)
  - A Biographical Sketch of William Franklin, read before the New Jersey Historical Society, Sept. 27, 1848 (2 copies), Whitehead, William A. (Reel 8)
  - Miscellaneous printed materials, 1753-1920s; 14 items (Reel 8)
    - American Museum, or, Universal Magazine vol. 7, 1790 May (Reel 8)
    - Aurora, General Advertiser (Philadelphia), 1794 July 30 (Reel 8)
    - Aurora, General Advertiser (Philadelphia), 1795 Jan. 26 (Reel 8)
    - Aurora, General Advertiser (Philadelphia), 1797 Dec. 9 (Reel 8)
    - Aurora, General Advertiser (Philadelphia), 1804 Aug. 11 (Reel 8)
    - Boston Gazette and County Journa (facsimiles), 1770 Mar. 12 (Reel 8)
    - Engraving of the Annual Medal of the Royal Society (15 sheets), 1753 December (Reel 8)
    - Maps, n.d. (Reel 8)
    - The New-England Courant (facsimile), 1723 Feb. 11 (Reel 8)
    - Newspaper clippins, 1870s-1920s (Reel 8)
    - Order of Exercises at the Inauguration of the Statue of Benjamin Franklin (Boston: George C. Rand and Avery, 1856) (Reel 8)
    - Photo portraits, with manuscript notes and fragments (Reel 8)
    - "Souvenirs" of George Bacon Wood, 1853-1879 (Reel 8)
    - Ticket of admission to the Philadelphia Tea Party, commemorating centenary of the Boston Tea Party, 1873 (Reel 8)
  - Bound volumes, 1766-1865; 11 items
    - Lessons for Children, From Two to Four Years old (Philadelphia: Benjamin Franklin Bache, 1788), Anonymous (Reel 8)
    - Lessons for Children, From Two to Four Years old (Philadelphia: Benjamin Franklin Bache, 1788), Anonymous (Reel 8)
    - "Examination of Dr. Franklin," pages taken from unknown magazine and bound1766-1774, taken from unknown volume, Anonymous (Reel 8)
    - "Scrapbook," contains manuscript and printed materials, Bache, Charles Meigs, 1829-1890 (Reel 8)
    - A Little Plain English, Addressed to the People of the United States (Philadelphia: Thomas Bradford, 1795), Cobbett, William (Reel 8)
    - Selectae E Veteri Testamento (Philadelphia: Benjamin Franklin Bache, 1789), Davidson, James, ed. (Reel 8)
    - Truth Will Out! The Ful Charges of the Tories Against the Editor of the Aurora Repelled by Positive Proof (Philadelphia: Benjamin Franklin Bache, 1798), Duane, William (Reel 8)
    - A Narrative of the Events Which Followed Bonaparte's Campaign in Russia (Hartford: George Sheldon, 1814), Dunlap, William (Reel 8)
    - The Decline and Fall of the English System of Finance (Philadelphia: John Page, 1796), Paine, Thomas, 1737-1809 (Reel 8)
    - Biographical Memoir of Franklin Bache (Philadelphia: J. B. Lippincott, 1865), Wood, George Bacod (Reel 8)
    - "Stud book" of the descendants of Benjamin Franklin Bache (manuscript), Bache, Emily Hinds (Reel 9)